Jason Omemu

Front-end Web Developer

Creative front-end developer with a flair for making elegant sites quickly. Worked on the front-end for the websites of some solutions for a few national projects. Outsourced to develop the client-side of an archives web app for Shell Nigeria(Port Harcourt) and greatly improved information retrieval time. Passionate about accessibility and performant web sites. Computer Science major certified by Udacity (Sponsored by Google) and Udemy. Also undertaken several courses on Frontend Masters and other platforms.

Experience

2017-07 - Intern Developer

2017-08 Southbridge Software Ltd

Added content for the School Management System project.

Developed a page for the app.

Worked with the team using Microsoft Teams and Git

2018-06 - Freelance Developer

2018-12 Shell Nigeria Ltd (Port Harcourt)

Developed the frontend for an archives web app and improved on the existing information system by eliminating time-consuming protocol and reducing

information retrieval time from a few days to minutes.

2020-01 - Intern Front-End Engineer

2020-09 Sysnet Software Solutions

Developed the front-end for websites involving the Federal Ministry of Communications and Digital Economy of Nigeria and a project bid for Nigeria Investment Promotion Commission.

Education

2015-09 - Afe Babalola University (ABUAD)

2019-05 BSc Computer Science

2008-09 - Greenoak International School

2014-06 WASSCE (West African Senior School Certificate Examination) and IGCSE

(International General Certificate of Secondary Education)

Student Activities

2019-01 - Afe Babalola University

2019-03 Managed the football team for the Sciences faculty.

Guided the 4th year team to the finals of the intra-college tournament

2012-03 - Greenoak International School

2012-04 President of the JETS (Junior Engineers, Technicians and Scientists) Club

Oversaw the development of 3 school projects.

2010-10 - Greenoak International School

2011-06 Head Boy

2012-09 - Greenoak International School

2013-06 Sports Prefect

Personal Info

Phone

+2347017936023

E-mail

jason.omemu@gmail.com

Date of birth

1997-01-30

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/jason-omemu

Skills

Proficient in Vanilla Javascript

Proficient in developing with React.js

+ Redux/Context API/Hooks

Teamwork

Continuous Learning

Problem Solving

Critical Thinking

Proficient at working with algorithms

Proficient with Design and Human Computer Interaction (HCI) concepts

High adaptability and collaboration skills

Proficiency in Git and Github

Proficient with Node.js, Node
Package Manager (NPM) and Yarn

Proficient with MySQL, Relational and Non-Relational Database Concepts

Familiar with Express.js and GraphQL

Proficient with semantic HTML5 and CSS3

Proficient with Adobe's Photoshop and Illustrator

Leadership

Languages

English, fluent (First Language)

Spanish, A1 level (Communicative in writing and speaking)

Certificates and Awards

2020-11	The Complete React Developer in 2021, ZTM Academy
2019-05	The Complete Web Developer in 2019, ZTM Academy
2018-11	Front-end Web Developer Nanodegree
2018-08	Google Africa Scholarship Certificate of Completion
2013-06	Awarded 1st place in School Proprietress' Essay Competition
2013-03	Awarded Best Speaker at AISEN (Association of International School Educators of Nigeria) Debate Competition
2011-06	Awarded Dux Award given to the best student in the school
2010-06	Awarded Dux Award given to the best student in the school

Conferences

2018-05

2018-06	Andela Learning Community (ALC) 3.0 Regional Meetup 2.0
2018-06	Andela Learning Community (ALC) 3.0 Regional Meetup 3.0
2019-03	Brand Development and Digital Marketing Conference (Exhibited a Web App to show how web sites can be used for brand development as well as other
	purposes such as games.)

Andela Learning Community (ALC) 3.0 Regional Meetup 1.0

Interests

Football (Soccer)

Music

Al and Robotics

Languages and Cultures

Geography

Fine and Applied Art

German, A1 level - Certified (Communicative in writing and speaking)

Dutch, A1 level (Communicative in writing and speaking)